Alberto Silva

Front End Developer

www.albertosilva.me asilvadesigns@gmail.com (301) 275-0678

Hello

My name is Alberto Silva and I'm an ambitious learner with an insatiable curiosity. In the past 6 years I've effectively adapted to my assigned mediums and roles. My experience includes 3D art, graphic design, web design, and most recently web development.

In Dec 2010 I graduated Full Sail University with a Course Director's Award in environment modeling and texturing. I spent the next two years taking on freelance projects and learning web design. I landed a full time position as a web designer in 2013.

I'm currently working as a front end developer at DealerOn with a focus on ui design and css architecture. I work closely with the development and design team; providing ui kits, mockups and live wireframes.

Skills

I am an expert in: Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, and SASS. I am proficient in: jQuery and JavaScript. I employ these methodologies: BEM, ITCSS, OOCSS.

- Layout and Typography
- · Responsive Web Design
- sass/css Architecture
- User Interface Design

Tools

The following have proven to be invaluable:

- Batch
- Bootstrap
- Paper

- Illustrator
- Cmder
- Pencil

- InDesign
- Git
- Photoshop
- Gulp
- Sublime
- Wordpress
- Vim

Employment

WEB DESIGNER
DealerOn | 2013–2014

- · Designed banners, graphics, and mockups.
- · Ensure cross-browser compatibility.
- Helped land 2 million dollar contract through responsive web design product integration.
- Maintain HTML/css for over 500 sites.

INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER
DealerOn | 2014–2015

- Prepare course materials, pitch to managers, design and develop class site and projects.
- · Review and critique student progress.
- Taught 13 employees (8 non-technical, 5 designers) HTML/css and Boostrap fundamentals through weekly classes. One non-technical is now a web designer while others are now leads of or promoted within their departments.

FRONT END DEVELOPER
DealerOn | 2015-Present

- Authored scss framework based on Bootstrap to extend functionality while retaining backwards-compatibility with sites using older versions of Bootstrap.
- · Design and develop live wireframes.
- Develop engaging JavaScript ui functionality.
- Provide ui component library and style guide.
- Work closely with team of 14 developers and 8 designers under guidance of Art Director.

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE DEGREE Full Sail University | 2007–2010

- Received Course Director's Award for excellence in 3D modeling and texturing.
- Work through rigorous deadlines in groups to accomplish an onslaught of projects that span the entire 3D pipeline.